A Guide to the Papers of Alice Jackson Stuart, 1913-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series IV: Subject & Topical Files (Box 30)
  - Religion - Virginia Interfaith Center for Public Policy 1990-1991 (Box 52)
  - Richmond Public Schools, Richmond, VA - Field Trip Directory 1955-1956 (Box 52)
  - Richmond Urban Forum (3 folders) 1994-2000, n.d. (Box 52)
  - Randall Robinson of Transafrica - Radio Transcripts 1998 (Box 52)
  - Rodman Jobs Corps Training Center, New Bedford, Massachusetts 1966, n.d. (Box 52)
  - Professor Charles T. Russell (1875----1942) 1994 (Box 52)
  - Rutgers University - Fundamentals of Core Curriculum Course - Class Papers 1955-1960, n.d. (Box 52)
  - Rutgers State University Workshop for High School English Teachers 1959, n.d. (Box 52)
  - Rutgers State University Workshops on Human Relations (2 folders) 1948-1963, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Rutgers State University Workshops on Human Relations - Correspondence 1960-1962 (Box 53)
  - Senior Center of Richmond 1992 (Box 53)
  - Serwa Awards 1989, 1992 (Box 53)
  - Smith College 1934-1935 (Box 53)
  - Social Issues 1955-1994, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare - Report n.y. May 14 (Box 53)
  - Student Opinion re Education 1965 (Box 53)
  - The Studio Museum in Harlem, New York (3 folders) 1968-2000, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Granver Paige Thomas (1923- ) - World War II Diary and Letters 1943-1944 (Box 54)
  - Thomas Jefferson High School, Los Angeles 1951-1954, n.d. (Box 54)
  - Treble Clef and Book Lovers Club 1988-1998 (Box 54)
  - Dr. Thomas Wyatt Turner 1976-1977 (Box 54)
  - Union College, Plainfield, New Jersey 1975, n.d. (Box 54)
  - Union County, Plainfield, New Jersey 1979 (Box 54)
  - United Methodist Junior Colleges - Newsletters 1971-1972 (Box 54)
  - University of Southern California 1954 (Box 54)
  - University of Virginia - "Blacks and the University of Virginia: An Overview 1819-1987" compiled by Ervin L. Jordan, Jr. (for Alice Jackson, see pages 7-8) 1987 (Box 54)
  - University of Virginia - The Civil Rights Lawyers Documentary Project -Alice Jackson 1987 (Box 54)
  - University of Virginia Application - Copies of Correspondence concerning (2 folders) 1934-1937, n.d. (Box 54)
  - University of Virginia - First Graduate School Black Applicants n.d (Box 54)
  - University of Virginia Application - News Clippings 1935 (Box 54)
  - University of Virginia Application - Student Response 1935 (Box 54)
  - University of Virginia "The Road to Brown" Film Poster (oversize) 1991 (Box 54)
  - Valentine Museum 1985-2000 (Box 54)
  - Vassar College Eleanor Roosevelt Centennial Conference 1953-1984 (Box 55)
  - Vassar College Eleanor Roosevelt Centennial Conference Poster (oversize) 1984 (Box 55)
  - Vietnam War 1962-1970 (Box 55)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University 1990-1994 (Box 55)
  - Virginia Historical Society 1983-2000 (Box 55)
  - Virginia Historical Society - Teachers' Institute Reunion 1995 (Box 55)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts 1984-2000 (Box 55)
  - Virginia Out-of-State Graduate Aid Program, 1936-1950 ca. 1956 (Box 55)
  - Virginia Union University 1916-2000 (Box 55)
  - Virginia Union University - Class Reunion 60-year Certificate 1994 (Box 56)
  - Virginia Union University - Commencement 1935-1992 (Box 56)
  - Virginia Union University - Community Learning Week 1986-1995 (Box 56)
  - Virginia Union University - Conference at Kings Mountain 1931 (Box 56)
  - Virginia Union University - Dedication of L. Douglas Wilder Library 1997-1998 (Box 56)
  - Virginia Union University - Programs 1957-1999 (Box 56)
  - The Virginia Writers Club 1989-1995 (Box 56)
  - Westfield Public Schools - Westfield, New Jersey 1962-1963 (Box 56)
  - L. Douglas Wilder 1988-1995 (Box 56)
  - L. Douglas Wilder - Inauguration 1990 (Box 56)
  - L. Douglas Wilder - Inauguration - Commemorative Issue of Reprints from Richmond Times-Dispatch and The Richmond News Leader(oversize) 1990 (Box 56)
- Series V: Educational Files and Research Materials (Box 56)
  - Bibliography - American Indians 1972 (Box 57)
  - Bibliography - European Drama by F.W. Chandler n.d. (Box 57)
  - Bibliography - Literary Criticism by F.W. Chandler n.d. (Box 57)
  - Bibliographies compiled by Alice Jackson Stuart re Black America n.d. (Box 57)
  - Bibliographies of Black History and Culture 1953, 1968, n.d. (Box 57)
  - Bibliographies of Black Literature 1971, 1987, n.d. (Box 57)
  - Bibliographies concerning Black Artists and Theater n.d. (Box 57)
  - Bibliographies concerning Civil Rights and Desegregation 1967, n.d. (Box 57)
  - Bibliographies concerning Education 1972, n.d. (Box 57)
  - Bibliographies concerning Women Writers of non-Western World and other Cultures n.d. (Box 57)
  - Book and Publication Lists n.d. (Box 57)
  - Child Growth and Development 1955-1959 (Box 57)
  - Critical Analysis 1959, n.d. (Box 57)
  - Curriculum Reform 1965, 1969, n.d. (Box 57)
  - Drama and Films 1966, n.d. (Box 57)
  - Filmstrip "The Role of the Male in the Family" - Text n.d. (Box 57)
  - The Gifted Child 1957-1958, n.d. (Box 57)
  - Grading n.d. (Box 58)
  - Grammar n.d. (Box 58)
  - High School Teaching 1953, 1960 (Box 58)
  - History 1963, 1996 (Box 58)
  - Illustrated Chart of American Flags n.d. (Box 58)
  - The Junior and Community College 1965, n.d. (Box 58)
  - Language n.d. (Box 58)
  - Lesson Plans - Evaluation n.d. (Box 58)
  - Liberal Arts Education n.d. (Box 58)
  - Library Resources 1959, n.d. (Box 58)
  - Low Income Students 1963, 1965, n.d. (Box 58)
  - Miscellaneous Educational Topics and Organizations 1954-1981, n.d. (Box 58)
  - Penmanship n.d. (Box 58)
  - Pima College - The Unit Learning System 1972, n.d. (Box 58)
  - Poetry Samples n.d. (Box 58)
  - Radio and Education, including Federal Communications Commission Information 1964-1965, n.d. (Box 58)
  - Radio and Education - "Bronze Tones" Program 1950, n.d. (Box 58)
  - Readability Formulas and Studies (2 folders) 1964, n.d. (Box 59)
  - Reading 1965-1974, n.d. (Box 59)
  - Research Materials - Africa (2 folders) 1961-1999, n.d. (Box 59)
  - Research Materials - Africa and Black Studies Dissertation Bibliography 1941, 1980, n.d. (Box 59)
  - Research Materials re Ballad of John Henry n.d. (Box 59)
  - Research Materials re Black Artist - Copy of Dissertation "The Social Milieu and the Black Artist in America 1900-1940" by Althea Bulls Williams 1972 Dec (Box 59)
  - Research Materials - Black Artists 1976-2000, n.d. (Box 59)
  - Research Materials - Blacks and Education 1967-1984, n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - "Black Heritage: A History of Afro-Americans" co-produced by Columbia University and WCBS-TV 1969 (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Black History 1944-1995, n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Black Leadership in Theater n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Black Literature 1968-1994, n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Black Media 1969-1996, n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Blacks in Medical Fields 1954-1996 (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Black Musicians, Singers and Performers (2 folders) 1954-1999, n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials re the Caribbean Islands and Literature 1975, 1985, n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Child Development 1962-1995, n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Civil Rights Movement 1959-1998, n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Civil War 1961-1984, n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Glass Manufacture n.d. (Box 60)
  - Research Materials - Harper's New Monthly Magazine(copies of articles re African-Americans from ca. 1850-1860's) n.d. (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Roland Hayes - A Tribute 1996 (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Langston Hughes 1986-1988, n.d. (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Illustrations of African-Americans in Harper's Weekly and other magazines of the time (oversize) 1866-1883 (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Israel 1948-1964, n.d. (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - John Keats 1950, n.d. (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Alice Dunbar Nelson 1968-1991 (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Alice Dunbar Nelson - An In-Depth Portrait of Alice Dunbar Nelson1974 (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Old English Poetry, including Beowulf1958, n.d. (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Richmond 1952-1998 (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Richmond - "The Battle Over Carver: A Struggle for Neighborhood Identity" in The Richmond Review1989 Jun (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Social Sciences Reprints 1938-1965 (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Maggie Lena Walker 1944, 1985-1998 (Box 61)
  - Research Materials - Maggie Lena Walker n.d. (Box 62)
  - Research Materials - Women's Studies 1975-1994, n.d. (Box 62)
  - Search for Identity Unit developed by Sheila A Schlawin n.d. (Box 62)
  - Speech and Public Speaking n.d. (Box 62)
  - Student Teaching 1960-1964, n.d. (Box 62)
  - Syllabi - African-American Literature Courses 1967-1987, n.d. (Box 62)
  - Syllabi - Miscellaneous 1964-1971 (Box 62)
  - Teacher Education and Qualifications 1964, n.d. (Box 62)
  - Television and Education (3 folders) 1952-1981, n.d. (Box 62)
  - Television, Writing for n.d. (Box 62)
  - Testing 1953-1984, n.d. (Box 62)
  - Testing Samples 1937-1958, n.d. (Box 63)
  - Testing Samples - Literature and English Composition 1959, 1976, n.d. (Box 63)
  - Thinking Activities 1960, n.d. (Box 63)
  - Values Clarification n.d. (Box 63)
  - Vocabulary and Spelling 1964, n.d. (Box 63)
  - Vocational Education in Negro High School in Virginia ca. 1952 (Box 63)
  - Writing and Composition 1963-1994, n.d. (Box 63)
  - Student Roll Books - RESTRICTED (Box 64)